Mizzu Cho

Austin, Texas, United States



mizzucho@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/mizzu-cho-983522178

Summary

My story * I always felt like I have been missing a piece inside of my heart working in the medical field before the pandemic. Reflecting on myself during the quarantine, I realized I have been constantly exposing myself to creative projects over time, such as helping out the restaurant with social media exposure and constantly suggesting peers to create creative photoshoots with me. I found myself truly thriving by collaborating with other artists to create a product that is unique to our team's personality. Then, I had an undeniably fortunate opportunity to be trained as a UX UI designer under three amazing mentors at CareerFoundry from Jan 2021 to Dec 2021. After a long time in front of the computer and sketching wireframes, I can confidently tell you:

Hi * I'm a creative designer based in Austin, TX. I design to humanize the product and vocalize the story. I want to work with other dreamers to create a genuine, emotional connection between the product and the target audience. It has not been an easy ride ever since I made the turn from the medical field to the design field, but nothing has made me feel more alive than the way design has been challenging me to become a better person.

UX Portfolio:

https://www.behance.net/mizzucho

Email:

mizzucho@gmail.com

Skills:

Creative problem-solving, agile design process, competitive analysis, user research, information architecture, card sorting, usability testing, user journey, user flows, wireframing, prototyping, etc.

Skills in training:

Frontend development, 3D illustration, creative photography, minimal line illustrations, social media content creation etc.

Experience



Portrait Photographer

Nicetomizzu

Mar 2018 - Present (3 years 11 months +)

Story * A random spark could lead to a burning house. A random camera I bought with the first check earned working in the medical field has become the most important creative outlet and one of the burning passions I have. The friendships I built with strangers and the sweet freedom to be as creative as I want on Photoshop and Lightroom are undeniably rewarding. Photography has also taught me that the aesthetic of the picture only pleases the eyes, but the authentic story behind the pictures pleases the heart.

Responsibilities as a freelance photographer:

1. Self-taught basic photography skills: photoshoot management and client management

- 2. Self-taught photo editing skills: color grading on Adobe Lightroom and photo refinement on Adobe Photoshop
- 3. Communicated with clients to set up a time and place for a photoshoot
- 4. Created Instagram content such as graphics with a consistent color system, Instagram reels, and AR filters to keep my target audience engaged.
- 5. Created a logo and color system to solidify my brand personality
- 6. Managed each graduation season as a unique project
- 7. Documented progress and mistakes to constructively improve my verbal communication skills and photoshoot experience with my clients



Food Server + Social Media Manager

Chosun Korean BBQ

May 2019 - Aug 2021 (2 years 4 months)

Story * After working as a food server for 2 years, I convinced my manager about the potential growth in social media and offered to help out the restaurant with social media management.

Responsibilities as a social media manager:

- 1. Presented photoshoot and social media plans to the manager
- 2. Managed a photoshoot taking photos of food and then editing digital images to obtain the right look for the restaurant
- 3. Researched Korean restaurant-related topics
- 4. Created a graphic design that would solidify a brand identity
- 5. Prepared well-structured drafts using digital word processing and publishing platforms
- 6. Managed photography and videography while working as a food server simultaneously
- 7. Organized the design components in a communicative platform for the manager

Responsibilities as a social media manager:

- 1. Collaborated with 4-5 people to manage 100+ tables in a very fast-paced environment
- 2. Communicated any food allergy or special nutrition needs to kitchen staff
- 3. Accurately entered the food and drink order into the ordering system and physically delivered them to the appropriate table
- 4. Provided attentive service to diners, like refilling drinks as needed and checking their needs during meals
- 5. Promptly addressed any customer service issues and referred to management if and when necessary
- 6. Performed cleaning duties throughout the shift, such as at the service station, around the kitchen, and in the dining area



Food Server

Chosun Korean BBQ May 2019 - Feb 2020 (10 months)



Medical Receptionist

EVERGREEN FAMILY MEDICINE, P.C.

May 2018 - May 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Story * During the time I wanted to pursue my career in the medical field, I was able to connect with Dr. Kim on the medical mission trip and was offered the wonderful opportunity to work in a private family medicine clinic.

Responsibilities as a medical receptionist:

- 1. Maintained patient records and appointments
- 2. Obtained insurance information and co-payments from patients
- 3. Handled insurance and referral paperwork
- 4. Managed incoming patient calls at the front desk
- 5. Transferred physical records into a digital system as EHR
- 6. Made follow-up appointments for patients and call patients to confirm appointments Contacts bumped patients and reschedule appointments
- 7. Assisted Korean patients with language barriers with English speaking medical assistants

Education

CF CareerFoundry

UX Immersion, UX Design Program Apr 2021 - Dec 2021

The University of Texas at Austin

Bachelor's degree, Biology, General 2016 - 2020 with pre-healthcare certificate

Licenses & Certifications

- in Shane Snow on Storytelling LinkedIn
- in Project Management Foundations LinkedIn
- in Agile Project Leadership LinkedIn
- in Transitioning from Waterfall to Agile Project Management LinkedIn
- Cert Prep: PMI Agile Certified Practitioner (PMI-ACP)® LinkedIn
- in Agile Foundations LinkedIn

Skills

Agile Project Management • Qualitative & Quantitative Research Methodologies • User Experience Design (UED) • User Interface Design • User Research • Information Architecture • Portrait Photography • social media marketing • Direct Patient Care • Agile Methodologies